How does a bastard, orphan, son of a whore and a scotsman
Dropped in the middle of a forgotten spot in the Carribean
By Providence, impoverished in squalor
Grow up to be a hero and a scholar?
The ten-dollar Founding Father without a father
Got a lot farther
By working a lot harder
By being a lot smarter
By fourteen, they placed him in charge of a trading charter
And every day, while slaves were being slaughtered
And carted away across the waves
He struggled and kept his guard up
Inside, he was longing for something to be a part of
The brother was ready to beg, steal, borrow, or barter
Then a hurricane came, and devastation rained
Our man saw his future drip-dripping down the drain
Put a pencil to his temple and connected it to his brain
And he wrote his first refrain, a testament to his pain
Well, the word got around, they said, "This kid is insane, man."
Took up a collection just to send him to the mainland
Get your education, don't forget from whence you came
And the world is gonna know your name
What's your name, man?
Alexander Hamilton
My name is Alexander Hamilton
And there are a million things I haven't done
But just you wait
Just you wait
When he was ten, his father split, full of it, debt-ridden
Two years later, see Alex and his mother, bed-ridden
Half-dead, sitting in their own sick, the scent thick
And Alex got better, but his mother went quick
Moved in with a cousin, the cousin committed suicide
Left him with nothing but ruined pride, something new inside
A voice saying
Alex, you gotta fend for yourself
He started retreating and reading every treatise on the shelf
There would've been nothing left to do for someone less astute
He would've been dead and destitute, without a cent of restitution
Started working, clerking for his late mother's landlord
Trading sugar cane and rum and other things he can't afford
Scamming
For every book he can get his hands on
Planning for the future, see him now as he stands on
The bow of a ship
Headed for a new land
In New York, you can be a new man
In New York, you can be a new man (Just you wait)
In New York
Just you wait
Alexander Hamilton
We are waiting in the wings for you
You could never back down
You never learned to take your time
Alexander Hamilton
America Sings for you
Do they know what you overcame?
Do they know you rewrote the game?
The world will never be the same
The ship is in the harbor now, see if you can spot him (Just you wait)
Another immigrant coming up from the bottom
His enemies destroyed his rep, and America forgot him
We fought with him
Me, I died for him
Me, I trusted him
Me, I loved him
And me
I'm the damn fool that shot him
There are a million things I haven't done
But just you wait
What's your name, man?
Alexander Hamilton